<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Samuel Debruyn</title>
    <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Samuel Debruyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 19:56:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cirqus demo</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/cirqus-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 19:56:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/cirqus-demo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In my graduation year I had to demonstrate how you can implement the CQRS principle in .NET. I went looking for a few CQRS frameworks and I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/d60/Cirqus&#34;&gt;Cirqus&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s the easiest way to get started with &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/CQRS.html&#34;&gt;CQRS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dn589792.aspx&#34;&gt;event sourcing&lt;/a&gt; in .NET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then developed this simple project which demonstrates the basic concepts of &lt;a href=&#34;http://dddcommunity.org/learning-ddd/what_is_ddd/&#34;&gt;domain driven design&lt;/a&gt;, CQRS and event sourcing using Cirqus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;domain:ed6c2b7a433a54340e9aa358e2099648&#34;&gt;Domain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is about a hotel called &lt;em&gt;Oditel&lt;/em&gt; (our school was called &lt;em&gt;Odisee&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;). There are 3 contexts with their aggregate roots:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Booking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project has the following layers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain: models and services (interfaces)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infrastructure: everything related to Cirqus, implementations of the services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation: this layer isn&amp;rsquo;t really a complete layer. It&amp;rsquo;s just a simple console app to demonstrate how the domain and infrastructure layers work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application and presentation layers are out of the scope of this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The console app goes through the followings steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create 4 rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create 2 customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let a customer book 2 rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the booking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extra-features:ed6c2b7a433a54340e9aa358e2099648&#34;&gt;Extra features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The events and most important &lt;em&gt;views&lt;/em&gt; are stored in SQL Server (Local DB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an extra view that keeps statistics of bookings per room per quarter. This view is rendered to &lt;strong&gt;MongoDB&lt;/strong&gt;, so you also need a local MongoDB server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few code diagrams to visualize how each layer interacts with the other layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created 4 branches with the 4 steps you have to take when developing a domain driven designed project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slides:ed6c2b7a433a54340e9aa358e2099648&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that demo also goes a presentation (in Dutch) which you can download &lt;a href=&#34;https://onedrive.live.com/redir?resid=B5240A36EC9AE039!485572&amp;amp;authkey=!AFa6VJYzeHPv4hI&amp;amp;ithint=file%2cpptx&#34;&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;. Let me know if the link is broken (I tend to move my files in my OneDrive around quite a lot).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Bad Wolf</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/big-bad-wolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 22:23:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/big-bad-wolf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is simple social media client written in C#. It was a school project we made in a team of 4 students. This was our first project in C# and the goal was to learn about&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi Document Interfaces (MDI) with Windows Forms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using &lt;a href=&#34;http://visualstudio.com&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Online&lt;/a&gt; (Team Foundation Services) to work with scrum, sprints&amp;hellip; The burndown chart was more important than the code or the finished application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;usage of APIs / working with SDKs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(an introduction to) async code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this social media client, you could connect your Facebook, Twitter and Instagram accounts and view all the posts in your timeline/activity feed in a single window. Every post had a background color matching the &lt;em&gt;theme&lt;/em&gt; of the social network it was published on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree, the GUI was terrible and the code wasn&amp;rsquo;t much better. But we had to start &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt;, right? I&amp;rsquo;ve made the source available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/BigBadWolf&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penguin Planner</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/penguin-planner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 22:23:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/penguin-planner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Penguin Planner is a school project we made in team of 4 students. The goal of the project was to learn about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;layered applications (seperating data, business/domain, presentation&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting an application to a database without using plain (T-)SQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multilingual applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of Penguin Planner was a replacement for a tool like &lt;a href=&#34;http://blackboard.com&#34;&gt;BlackBoard&lt;/a&gt;. It was a tool made for students and teachers. They had to be able to manage their courses, tasks, tests&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/viperneo/winforms-modernui&#34;&gt;MetroFramework&lt;/a&gt; to bring the &lt;em&gt;Modern UI&lt;/em&gt; design to a Windows Forms application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application is written in C# and the complete source code is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/PenguinPlanner&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. You should be able to build the application after downloading the referenced nuget packages. However, you&amp;rsquo;d need to recreate the database and change the connection string to be able to run it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RoboRally</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/roborally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 17:02:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/roborally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RoboRally is a simple game written in Java, based on the board game &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RoboRally&#34;&gt;RoboRally&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://company.wizards.com/&#34;&gt;Wizards of the Coast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game was a semester project in which a pair of students had to learn the basics of object oriented programming, source code control and extreme programming. The project was part of the course &lt;a href=&#34;https://onderwijsaanbod.kuleuven.be/syllabi/n/H01P1AN.htm#activetab=doelstellingen_idp2111760&#34;&gt;Object Oriented Programming&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://distrinet.cs.kuleuven.be/people/eric&#34;&gt;Prof. E. Steegmans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code contains a lot of documentation; this project is really about the code and not about the game itself. Our final version is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/OGProborally&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>asr.ac</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/asr-ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 21:17:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/asr-ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2015 the General Student Council (ASR / GSC) Odisee elected me to be their IT manager. I became responsible for several services, one of which was their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website is built with &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and stored on a shared hosting account. I customized the theme and setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/&#34;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;. As the website was hacked in the months before I became the administrator, I had to &lt;a href=&#34;http://sa.muel.be/2015/recovering-a-hacked-wordpress/&#34;&gt;restore&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://sa.muel.be/2015/hardening-your-wordpress-security/&#34;&gt;secure&lt;/a&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed this website from June 2015 until July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material Design Lite theme for Hugo</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/material-design-theme-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 13:43:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/material-design-theme-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I wanted to learn more about &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; while developing &lt;a href=&#34;http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/this-blog/&#34;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://sa.muel.be/2015/material-lite-theme-for-hugo/&#34;&gt;created&lt;/a&gt; a new theme for Hugo. It is mostly plain HTML, CSS and JavaScript, but it also contains some &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/pkg/html/template/&#34;&gt;Go Templating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme is based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getmdl.io/templates/index.html&#34;&gt;blog template&lt;/a&gt; from Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getmdl.io/&#34;&gt;Material Design Lite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/hugo-material-lite&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and I host &lt;a href=&#34;http://materialexample.sa.muel.be/&#34;&gt;a demo&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SamShack</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/samshack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 13:26:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/samshack/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In January 2014 I had to develop a webshop in PHP for a school project. At the time we just learnt about MVC and the best framework for the job seemed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cakephp.org&#34;&gt;CakePHP&lt;/a&gt;. My webshop had responsive design and was very fast (high scores on PageSpeed and Yahoo YSlow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The webshop itself is no longer available online, but the source code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/MI4webshop&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;functional-requirements:8f252d2e6836bd8c7f9c98107e37888e&#34;&gt;Functional requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configuration-panel:8f252d2e6836bd8c7f9c98107e37888e&#34;&gt;Configuration panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRUD actions for every kind of data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The administrator has to log in to be able to do anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The administrator must be able to create other administrative user accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The administrator can view the ERD of the webshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;client-site:8f252d2e6836bd8c7f9c98107e37888e&#34;&gt;Client site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Products have categories and can be sorted and filtered by category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shopping cart which can be modified at any time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shoppers have to create user accounts to buy anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only registered users can view the stock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stock needs to automatically updated after a sale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirmation emails for all kinds of actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password reset mails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History of purchases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalized recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B&amp;B Go Eun API</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/bb-go-eun-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 13:45:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/bb-go-eun-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This API was made for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/bb-go-eun/&#34;&gt;Android app B&amp;amp;B Go Eun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is written in PHP and built on top of &lt;a href=&#34;http://cakephp.org/&#34;&gt;CakePHP&lt;/a&gt;. The API returns all results in JSON and is follows most the RESTful API design principles. It relies on a MySQL database for all of its data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the assignment was graded in June 2014, it&amp;rsquo;s possible that the API is no longer available. The source code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/MI4API&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>this blog</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 12:03:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/this-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is made with &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://sa.muel.be/2015/an-introduction-to-hugo-a-static-site-generator/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about it when I switched from &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/sa.muel.be-hugo&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B&amp;B Go Eun app</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/bb-go-eun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 12:03:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/bb-go-eun/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This Android app was a school project I made with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/talipovdaniyar&#34;&gt;another student&lt;/a&gt;. We established several goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-requirements:fc46f81bf6fdf8b7e4084cd9b0161e8c&#34;&gt;Technical requirements:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had to learn a lot about PHP and Android development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app had to connect with &lt;a href=&#34;http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/bb-go-eun-api/&#34;&gt;a (RESTful) API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The API had to connect with a database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app had to be very simple so we could demonstrate the main goals (connection with API).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had to made sure that everything worked fine and all known bugs were fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had to write a few pages of documentation for our lecturer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;functional-requirements:fc46f81bf6fdf8b7e4084cd9b0161e8c&#34;&gt;Functional requirements:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show information about available rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show contact information with links that open the diailer app, the email app, Google Maps&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show promotions coupled to rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the breakfast menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show nearby points of interest in a predefined range, sorted by distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assignment included finding a real client and the client we chose was a friend who owns a B&amp;amp;B on AirBnB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the assignment was graded in June 2014, it&amp;rsquo;s possible that the app is no longer available. The source code is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/MI4App&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go for Change</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/go-for-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 12:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/go-for-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go For Change is an Android app I wrote for a school project. It was actually part of another student&amp;rsquo;s internship, but since that student quit his internship, the client asked my lecturers if they knew another student who could finish the job. All I had was 2 weeks so I didn&amp;rsquo;t write any documentation and the code is quite messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application contains a questionnaire targeted to small business owners. The difficult part was the order of the questions. Some questions only had to be answered depending on the answers of previous questions and the client had to be able to change the questions, the possible answers and the order of the questions. I created a small SQLite database and a method to export the answered questions to a CSV file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This application is only visible in the Play Store for test users. The source is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/WePgoforchange&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the assignment was graded in June 2014, it&amp;rsquo;s possible that the app is no longer available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rood Fluweel Bali</title>
      <link>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/rood-fluweel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 16:06:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>s@muel.be (Samuel Debruyn)</author>
      <guid>http://sa.muel.be/portfolio/rood-fluweel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rood Fluweel Bali is a Windows Store app, designed for Windows 8.1 desktops and tablets. I made this app for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comm-it.be&#34;&gt;Comm-IT&lt;/a&gt; as part of a summer job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roodfluweel.be&#34;&gt;Rood Fluweel&lt;/a&gt; is a SaaS made on top of ASP.NET. It can manage ticketing, reservations, payments etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the Windows Store app is to make it easier to print and create tickets when a lot of people are coming through the entrance at once.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>